<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"> <body> <div xml:id="captions">

<p begin="00:00:01" end="00:00:06">I’m Tim Brooks. I’m the chief executive
of BMJ Group. The starting for this is that
</p>

<p begin="00:00:06" end="00:00:13">for very complex and multiple reasons government
in this country has gotten way behind the
</p>

<p begin="00:00:14" end="00:00:19">rest of the country in terms of the way it
uses technology to deal with the people it
</p>

<p begin="00:00:19" end="00:00:25">deals with, which is the citizens of this
country. It’s a cliché but you can book
</p>

<p begin="00:00:25" end="00:00:32">a flight in two minutes to anywhere in the
world on a screen in your home or even on
</p>

<p begin="00:00:33" end="00:00:38">your phone, and yet dealing with government
can involve paperwork and writing a cheque
</p>

<p begin="00:00:38" end="00:00:40">and putting something in the mail and all
that kind of stuff.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:40" end="00:00:45">At a very simple level it’s let’s make
sure that government just catches up with
</p>

<p begin="00:00:45" end="00:00:49">where its citizens find themselves in the
rest of their lives. Because the danger is
</p>

<p begin="00:00:49" end="00:00:54">not just about cost, and it’s not just about
efficiency, but it’s actually about relevance
</p>

<p begin="00:00:54" end="00:01:01">and engagement with the people who fund government.
Digital buy default; you could spend a lot
</p>

<p begin="00:01:02" end="00:01:09">of time wrestling with history and explaining
the 97 reasons why things are how they are
</p>

<p begin="00:01:09" end="00:01:15">and how they got that way. That’s just,
in many respects, a complete waste of time.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:15" end="00:01:21">So digital by default is Martha Lane Fox’s
slogan that she devised and attached to the
</p>

<p begin="00:01:21" end="00:01:28">strategy that government digital service is
pursuing, and it simply means it’s digital.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:28" end="00:01:33">If it isn’t digital, why is not digital?
It’s not about let’s understand all the
</p>

<p begin="00:01:33" end="00:01:38">reasons why we are where we are; it’s about
why are we going to be so simple going forward.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:38" end="00:01:42">The government making use of small and medium
businesses is a subject close to my heart
</p>

<p begin="00:01:42" end="00:01:49">because I actually run a medium-sized business.
There’s been a lot of discussion about how
</p>

<p begin="00:01:49" end="00:01:55">government procurement processes historically
have made it extremely difficult for anything
</p>

<p begin="00:01:55" end="00:02:01">other than very large and established suppliers
to complete in this space. And yet the reality
</p>

<p begin="00:02:01" end="00:02:06">as we know and as the government constantly
highlights when they’re talking about digital
</p>

<p begin="00:02:06" end="00:02:10">Britain, it’s often the smaller companies,
you know, the digital roundabout people in
</p>

<p begin="00:02:10" end="00:02:17">Shoreditch who might be a 20-person company,
who are driving change and being really innovative
</p>

<p begin="00:02:17" end="00:02:23">and inventing new services and taking costs
out of processes. Getting those smaller companies
</p>

<p begin="00:02:23" end="00:02:30">engaged will unleash a lot of creativity.
Without being rude to systems integrators,
</p>

<p begin="00:02:30" end="00:02:36">the big companies – and we use them ourselves
when we need to – they have a very fixed
</p>

<p begin="00:02:36" end="00:02:43">way of doing things, and it’s always a big
way of doing things. Often the way to solve
</p>

<p begin="00:02:43" end="00:02:48">these problems effectively and quickly is
to find small ways to solve them.
</p>



 </div> </body> </tt>