<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"> <body> <div xml:id="captions">

<p begin="00:00:00" end="00:00:05">You wouldn’t buy a car without a dashboard
and you wouldn’t run a service without a
</p>

<p begin="00:00:05" end="00:00:11">good understanding of how well it’s being
used by your customers, by businesses and
</p>

<p begin="00:00:11" end="00:00:18">citizens. I think the data is absolutely fundamental
to being able to take good decisions about
</p>

<p begin="00:00:19" end="00:00:24">the management of that service.
In the private sector, companies like Amazon
</p>

<p begin="00:00:24" end="00:00:31">and Twitter, they will go bust if they don’t
focus on the user needs for their customers.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:31" end="00:00:36">Government often is the only person providing
a particular service to citizens and businesses,
</p>

<p begin="00:00:36" end="00:00:41">but it’s no less important that we are responsive
to the needs of our users.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:41" end="00:00:48">Statistics don’t have a reputation for far-side
reading, it it’s valuable whether the data
</p>

<p begin="00:00:49" end="00:00:55">is numbers or whether it’s words to make
sure that there is a focused presentation
</p>

<p begin="00:00:55" end="00:01:01">to cut to the crux of what people need to
know in order to make the decisions about
</p>

<p begin="00:01:01" end="00:01:08">the services that they’re responsible for.
Too often data is given to people in enormous
</p>

<p begin="00:01:09" end="00:01:16">quantity and people find it difficult to filter
out what is essential and what is merely interesting.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:16" end="00:01:22">By making sure that the visual presentation
of these products are sharp, we hope to save
</p>

<p begin="00:01:22" end="00:01:27">time and to make sure that people focus on
the main thing.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:27" end="00:01:33">We think a consistent set of management information
for all departments is really, really important
</p>

<p begin="00:01:33" end="00:01:40">to get a set of benchmarks for what good looks
like across government services, but also
</p>

<p begin="00:01:41" end="00:01:47">to make sure that these services are focused
on the needs and the concerns of their users.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:47" end="00:01:54">So information relating to user satisfaction,
the cost per transaction for those services,
</p>

<p begin="00:01:56" end="00:02:03">the digitalisation of those services, how
digital they are, and the success rate is
</p>

<p begin="00:02:03" end="00:02:08">all really generically useful information,
regardless of what kind of service it is.
</p>



 </div> </body> </tt>