<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"> <body> <div xml:id="captions">

<p begin="00:00:01" end="00:00:07">I think that it is only ever likely to be
a success if you’re going through any kind
</p>

<p begin="00:00:07" end="00:00:12">of digital transformation, if you have absolute
support at the top of an organisation.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:12" end="00:00:17">It’s much better if digital is led and championed
by somebody who is responsible at board level
</p>

<p begin="00:00:17" end="00:00:21">for driving change throughout the organisation
and transformation.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:21" end="00:00:26">I think it’s really important to have big
hitters, if you will, at board level. Because
</p>

<p begin="00:00:26" end="00:00:30">when you’re having the conversations at
board level that says, “Should we invest
</p>

<p begin="00:00:30" end="00:00:35">in a piece of technology? Should we invest
in a particular approach? Should we deliver
</p>

<p begin="00:00:35" end="00:00:39">that change?” you need someone that understands
it. You need someone who understands it and
</p>

<p begin="00:00:39" end="00:00:41">can genuinely advocate for it.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:41" end="00:00:46">It needs to be somebody who has a real passion
for the subject and that can persuade their
</p>

<p begin="00:00:46" end="00:00:51">colleagues, and is a credible individual that
can persuade their colleagues of the reason
</p>

<p begin="00:00:51" end="00:00:52">for change.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:52" end="00:00:57">The benefits of digital by default are numerous.
I think what I would see as the principle
</p>

<p begin="00:00:57" end="00:01:01">benefit is that in order to drive the sort
of change that we, along with the rest of
</p>

<p begin="00:01:01" end="00:01:04">the public sector, are having to drive to
deliver better for less and critically, to
</p>

<p begin="00:01:04" end="00:01:08">take a huge amount of money out of the business
during the course of this spending review,
</p>

<p begin="00:01:08" end="00:01:11">we’ve got to change the paradigm of how
we’re working.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:11" end="00:01:15">It’s got to be thought of as a process of
dramatic transformation.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:15" end="00:01:19">What is important is that it’s taken seriously
by the people at the top.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:19" end="00:01:23">Politicians don’t like things going wrong,
and that tends to lead to a fairly risk averse
</p>

<p begin="00:01:23" end="00:01:30">approach to new ideas and new things. So my
advice would be find something which is really
</p>

<p begin="00:01:30" end="00:01:35">reasonably easy to do, try something different
and then move on from there.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:35" end="00:01:39">I think that the most important thing is that
the person feels as though they understand
</p>

<p begin="00:01:39" end="00:01:44">technology and can see it’s possibility,
and are not afraid to ask questions about
</p>

<p begin="00:01:44" end="00:01:47">the way technologies are used, and the way
that they might be used in the future.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:47" end="00:01:53">I think the secondary thing is also an ability
to inspire and lead and put out the art of
</p>

<p begin="00:01:53" end="00:01:54">the possible.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:54" end="00:01:59">To my mind, it’s not just about bringing
in digital experts who can tell us how to
</p>

<p begin="00:01:59" end="00:02:04">do the business differently; it’s about
re-thinking our business in a digital way.
</p>

<p begin="00:02:04" end="00:02:11">You genuinely need to understand what the
user needs today in language that they would
</p>

<p begin="00:02:11" end="00:02:15">understand, rather than language that the
organisation understands. They may not be
</p>

<p begin="00:02:15" end="00:02:20">the same thing. But also to recognise things
that may appear to be relatively small and
</p>

<p begin="00:02:20" end="00:02:23">minor, but actually are really big for those
users.
</p>

<p begin="00:02:23" end="00:02:29">I believe that as a country, we should help
unlock their full potential, and that is more
</p>

<p begin="00:02:29" end="00:02:34">achievable if they are able to use technology
than if they are not. And for me, government
</p>

<p begin="00:02:34" end="00:02:38">needs to take a lead in that, and it needs
to take the lead by creating brilliant services.
</p>

<p begin="00:02:38" end="00:02:42">It’s hard, you know, it’s hard when you’re
the lone voice, but I think the great news
</p>

<p begin="00:02:42" end="00:02:44">is that the tide is in your favour.
</p>

<p begin="00:02:44" end="00:02:49">We’re trying to reform and transform the
way we do business, so partly it’s about
</p>

<p begin="00:02:49" end="00:02:54">increasingly automating functions that we
provide, which makes it more efficient to
</p>

<p begin="00:02:54" end="00:03:00">provide them, but also makes it much better
for our users. People want us to be online
</p>

<p begin="00:03:00" end="00:03:04">now, they want to be able to do things online,
and we need to be able to be responding to
</p>

<p begin="00:03:04" end="00:03:04">that.
</p>

<p begin="00:03:04" end="00:03:08">We’ve got a great pilot project going in
Kent, which is looking at a virtual court,
</p>

<p begin="00:03:08" end="00:03:13">where we’ve had so far 2,500 people appear
in court on video technology instead of having
</p>

<p begin="00:03:13" end="00:03:18">to travel to court. This has so far saved
300 policeman hours. But it really just makes
</p>

<p begin="00:03:18" end="00:03:22">it much more convenient for people, and most
of the people that we deal with in justice,
</p>

<p begin="00:03:22" end="00:03:27">or many of them, are actually vulnerable or
they’re victims or they’re witnesses.
</p>

<p begin="00:03:27" end="00:03:31">So we’re trying to give them a better service,
and it also happens to be more efficient.
</p>

<p begin="00:03:31" end="00:03:35">I think that whoever is chosen as a digital
board member is likely to be somebody that
</p>

<p begin="00:03:35" end="00:03:41">feels inspired and feels keen to make sure
the message is spread, and I would urge them
</p>

<p begin="00:03:41" end="00:03:44">to do so both in, out of the board, and all
around it. This is complex change, this is
</p>

<p begin="00:03:44" end="00:03:48">hard change, and you’ve got to feel as thought
the person is somebody that you would want
</p>

<p begin="00:03:48" end="00:03:52">to listen and will want to work with – if
not on a daily basis – but on a monthly,
</p>

<p begin="00:03:52" end="00:03:54">weekly, yearly basis. That’s the first thing.
</p>

<p begin="00:03:54" end="00:03:58">I think the second thing is you’ve also
got to make sure that you feel as though they’ve
</p>

<p begin="00:03:58" end="00:03:59">got that digital credibility.
</p>

<p begin="00:03:59" end="00:04:05">Well, at the heart of change is that people
feel it here.
</p>

<p begin="00:04:05" end="00:04:09">People change is they’re incentivised to
change. It was often we tend to assume that
</p>

<p begin="00:04:09" end="00:04:14">people will change because we’ve told them
to. Nobody ever changes because they’ve
</p>

<p begin="00:04:14" end="00:04:19">been threatened. They change to something
because they perceive it better. If you look
</p>

<p begin="00:04:19" end="00:04:24">at the way a number of us use internet banking
now, its because we perceive the service to
</p>

<p begin="00:04:24" end="00:04:28">be better and we perceive that being able
to do your banking at 11 o’clock at night
</p>

<p begin="00:04:28" end="00:04:31">is better than standing in a queue on a rainy
Saturday morning.
</p>

<p begin="00:04:31" end="00:04:37">The notion of innovation, which cycles very
quickly, where people try things out, they
</p>

<p begin="00:04:37" end="00:04:41">have an alpha release, a beta release and
then it’s live, all of those concepts are
</p>

<p begin="00:04:41" end="00:04:45">not things that are within the normal way
we do things. It’s not the way we do policy,
</p>

<p begin="00:04:45" end="00:04:49">it’s not the way you make laws, it’s not
the way we do our regular business. So getting
</p>

<p begin="00:04:49" end="00:04:56">that notion of agility into the way departments
think I think is going to be the real challenge.
</p>

<p begin="00:04:56" end="00:05:00">That notion that you’ll try something, you
might fail and then you’ll move onto something
</p>

<p begin="00:05:00" end="00:05:05">else, sounds fantastic when written down,
but actually making that happen when you’ve
</p>

<p begin="00:05:05" end="00:05:09">got to satisfy a minister who’s having a
hard time in parliament over something which
</p>

<p begin="00:05:09" end="00:05:14">you’ve tried and failed is something which
I think many civil servants would really struggle
</p>

<p begin="00:05:14" end="00:05:18">with. Because ultimately, we spend our time
trying not to put our ministers in harm’s
</p>

<p begin="00:05:18" end="00:05:18">way.
</p>

<p begin="00:05:18" end="00:05:24">I think that the opportunity is enormous.
All the momentum is with us, both the macro-economic
</p>

<p begin="00:05:24" end="00:05:28">environment, but also the potential to really
empower individuals through better use of
</p>

<p begin="00:05:28" end="00:05:33">technology, both inside and outside government.
But it needs to be bedded down and it needs
</p>

<p begin="00:05:33" end="00:05:38">to be brought into senior levels. It needs
to keep having that top support, it needs
</p>

<p begin="00:05:38" end="00:05:43">to have the board members in place and through
every single department, people who are able
</p>

<p begin="00:05:43" end="00:05:46">to affect the change and help with the change.
So I am optimistic but it’s going to be
</p>

<p begin="00:05:46" end="00:05:47">hard work.
</p>



 </div> </body> </tt>