<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"> <body> <div xml:id="captions">

<p begin="00:00:00" end="00:00:05">It's easy just to hear the cost savings part
of this but I'm looking at my notes from the
</p>

<p begin="00:00:05" end="00:00:11">remarks and I'm seeing 'User needs first and
foremost...', 'How does this make the user
</p>

<p begin="00:00:11" end="00:00:16">experience better?', 'What is the user need?
The most important question for any government
</p>

<p begin="00:00:16" end="00:00:19">service…'.
That's what those of us in the rest of the
</p>

<p begin="00:00:19" end="00:00:25">world found so inspiring about the Government
Digital Strategy. It's really as if for the
</p>

<p begin="00:00:25" end="00:00:32">first time, Government is doing the thing
that is so revolutionary out in Silicon Valley,
</p>

<p begin="00:00:33" end="00:00:39">which is you're building these lightweight
applications and if people don't like them,
</p>

<p begin="00:00:39" end="00:00:46">if people don't use them, they fail. And that
revolution is why we have seen such rapid
</p>

<p begin="00:00:46" end="00:00:53">change and such rapid development.
There has really become almost a cult of user
</p>

<p begin="00:00:54" end="00:00:59">centred design which has driven innovation
forward. And to see that being brought to
</p>

<p begin="00:00:59" end="00:01:03">government, where we're saying 'wait a minute,
we have a customer here, we have to satisfy
</p>

<p begin="00:01:03" end="00:01:10">that customer'. And the customer is not the
government, the customer is the citizen. That
</p>

<p begin="00:01:10" end="00:01:15">is a revolution.
And that's the revolution that we see here.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:15" end="00:01:22">When all of us who were working in open government
saw the UK Government Digital Strategy we
</p>

<p begin="00:01:22" end="00:01:28">were like 'this is the new bible for anyone
working in Government'. This is the document
</p>

<p begin="00:01:28" end="00:01:35">to study. Everybody around the world should
be following this. If we can apply that as
</p>

<p begin="00:01:35" end="00:01:42">our scripture for government best practices
at every level around the world I think we'll
</p>

<p begin="00:01:43" end="00:01:50">be doing a fantastic service because we need
to get away from this notion that government
</p>

<p begin="00:01:50" end="00:01:56">and the people are odds. And when you build
systems where the interfaces between government
</p>

<p begin="00:01:56" end="00:02:02">and citizens are - to use Jens's words - simple,
beautiful and easy to use, you really transform
</p>

<p begin="00:02:02" end="00:02:07">the very notion of government.
I've been using a wonderful quote that we
</p>

<p begin="00:02:07" end="00:02:14">discovered recently from Abraham Lincoln
where he said "the job of government is to
</p>

<p begin="00:02:14" end="00:02:20">do the things that the people cannot easily
or at all do by themselves". And we have to
</p>

<p begin="00:02:20" end="00:02:27">remember that Government is in fact an organ
of the body politic and serves that body politic.
</p>



 </div> </body> </tt>