<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"> <body> <div xml:id="captions">

<p begin="00:00:00" end="00:00:05">What you really want, if you're government,
is to make sure that you create service end
</p>

<p begin="00:00:05" end="00:00:12">points that will allow outside developers
to build applications against your data. That's
</p>

<p begin="00:00:12" end="00:00:15">something that is in the Government Digital
Strategy, it's like - we're not just going
</p>

<p begin="00:00:15" end="00:00:19">to build websites and apps, we're going to
build web services.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:19" end="00:00:24">Because when you publish those end points
then you can have a really productive hackathaon,
</p>

<p begin="00:00:24" end="00:00:30">somebody can say 'here's this government data,
I'm going to use it in a way that nobody expected',
</p>

<p begin="00:00:30" end="00:00:34">and that's when you get that incredible revolution.
On the the things that I've talked about for
</p>

<p begin="00:00:34" end="00:00:37">the last couple of years is the notion that
Government needs to start thinking of itself
</p>

<p begin="00:00:37" end="00:00:44">as a platform. In the same way that Apple
re-thought the mobile phone. In the old days
</p>

<p begin="00:00:45" end="00:00:50">with mobile phones the vendors went in the
back room with a couple of developers and
</p>

<p begin="00:00:50" end="00:00:55">companies and came up with 30 applications
'this is the phone'. Apple turned it into
</p>

<p begin="00:00:55" end="00:01:00">a platform and suddenly there are now 700,000
applications on the iPhone.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:00" end="00:01:05">And to me a real mark of success will be first
of all when government has figured out what
</p>

<p begin="00:01:05" end="00:01:12">is the minimal set of things that it absolutely
needs to do and then exposes a robust rich
</p>

<p begin="00:01:15" end="00:01:20">set of service end points that will allow
people out in the private sector add additional
</p>

<p begin="00:01:20" end="00:01:27">value to that minimal must-do set of things.
Then we can hit some real magic because we'll
</p>

<p begin="00:01:27" end="00:01:33">get more and more services for citizens with
more and more ingenuity without any procurement
</p>

<p begin="00:01:33" end="00:01:39">at all because the government made it possible
for people outside to build interesting things.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:39" end="00:01:46">I'm just reminded of a wonderful passage in
Ben Zander's TED talk from a few years back.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:46" end="00:01:53">He opened with an old story of the first British
shoe salesman who went to Africa.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:53" end="00:01:59">There were two different salesmen, and one
said "Uh! There's no opportunity here. Nobody
</p>

<p begin="00:01:59" end="00:02:05">here wears shoes" and the other one said "Send
more people! Nobody here wears shoes!"
</p>



 </div> </body> </tt>