<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"> <body> <div xml:id="captions">

<p begin="00:00:00" end="00:00:05">I'm Roo Reynolds and I'm a product
manager at GDS. OPG stands for Office of the
</p>

<p begin="00:00:05" end="00:00:11">Public Guardian, and that's one of the executive
bodies within the ministry of justice. The
</p>

<p begin="00:00:11" end="00:00:15">project that we're working with them on
is the lasting power of attorney. So if somebody's
</p>

<p begin="00:00:15" end="00:00:19">going to lose mental capacity and they want
to give somebody else power over their life,
</p>

<p begin="00:00:19" end="00:00:25">their financial affairs, and indeed all parts
of their life, then they need to have that
</p>

<p begin="00:00:25" end="00:00:32">person be given the power of attorney.
In the current system, that's a paper form
</p>

<p begin="00:00:35" end="00:00:39">and it requires you to enter your name and
your address multiple times on the same paper
</p>

<p begin="00:00:39" end="00:00:45">form. It's very easy to get it wrong; even
lawyers are not perfect when it comes to filling
</p>

<p begin="00:00:45" end="00:00:51">in these sorts of things, and it's often
done with the help of a solicitor or some
</p>

<p begin="00:00:51" end="00:00:56">other professional. Even they will frequently
make mistakes, so it's a painful process
</p>

<p begin="00:00:56" end="00:00:59">to go through at what could be a difficult
time in your life.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:59" end="00:01:06">We've been working with MOJ to think about
a product and build a prototype of a product
</p>

<p begin="00:01:07" end="00:01:13">that would allow somebody to grant the lasting
power of attorney to someone else digitally.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:13" end="00:01:20">ERTP stands for electoral registration transformation
programme. It's a programme within government
</p>

<p begin="00:01:21" end="00:01:27">run at the moment by the cabinet office. The
idea is to move from a system of household
</p>

<p begin="00:01:27" end="00:01:31">registration. So when you come to register
to vote, it's the head of the household
</p>

<p begin="00:01:31" end="00:01:36">that fills it in in this very kind of antiquated
way. So the government wants to do two things;
</p>

<p begin="00:01:36" end="00:01:42">we want to increase the accuracy of the electoral
register, but also the completeness, and those
</p>

<p begin="00:01:42" end="00:01:47">two goals go hand-in-hand.
We can often start with a pretty good idea
</p>

<p begin="00:01:47" end="00:01:53">of what the user needs for what a system will
be. But the sooner you can start testing that
</p>

<p begin="00:01:53" end="00:01:58">theory by putting something that works in
front of a group of users and hopefully lots
</p>

<p begin="00:01:58" end="00:02:05">of different sorts of users, then you can
validate that the user needs are actually
</p>

<p begin="00:02:05" end="00:02:09">useful to you and they're actually the things
that are going to make the product better.
</p>

<p begin="00:02:09" end="00:02:15">It can often mean starting small and then
building gradually, and not always knowing
</p>

<p begin="00:02:15" end="00:02:18">at the beginning what you're going to end
up building at the end. So it's quite good
</p>

<p begin="00:02:18" end="00:02:18">fun.
</p>



 </div> </body> </tt>