<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"> <body> <div xml:id="captions">

<p begin="00:00:00" end="00:00:05">I particularly wanted to work in the public
sector because I want to do work that’s
</p>

<p begin="00:00:05" end="00:00:06">of value to people.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:06" end="00:00:11">It’s not just about programming computers.
That’s one of the things that’s really,
</p>

<p begin="00:00:11" end="00:00:14">really key for the work that we do. That’s
part of what we do, and it’s certainly something
</p>

<p begin="00:00:14" end="00:00:20">that we need to be able to do, but we also
need to understand how people interact with
</p>

<p begin="00:00:20" end="00:00:25">computers. For example, how human beings actually
use them. That’s quite a subtle and difficult
</p>

<p begin="00:00:25" end="00:00:27">and challenging art.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:27" end="00:00:32">User research and user-centred design is a
pretty new field. It isn’t something that
</p>

<p begin="00:00:32" end="00:00:37">traditional software and IT projects have
necessarily embraced. It’s something that
</p>

<p begin="00:00:37" end="00:00:43">we need as designers to design. Only if we
get talking to people that are using these
</p>

<p begin="00:00:43" end="00:00:45">services can we make them better.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:45" end="00:00:52">Agile is a software development process that
has evolved, particularly in the online world,
</p>

<p begin="00:00:53" end="00:01:00">over the last 10, 15 years or so. It’s very
different to the traditional approaches that
</p>

<p begin="00:01:01" end="00:01:04">the government uses to run projects, such
as the Waterfall approach.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:04" end="00:01:08">In the Waterfall approach, which the government
uses for the majority of its work, we do an
</p>

<p begin="00:01:08" end="00:01:14">upfront piece of design where people sit in
a room and write a document and design what
</p>

<p begin="00:01:14" end="00:01:18">the system’s going to be capable of. We
then often do some procurement to go and get
</p>

<p begin="00:01:18" end="00:01:23">the people or the technical resource or specialists
to build the system. We then go into a build
</p>

<p begin="00:01:23" end="00:01:27">phase where the system is actually built.
These can take months these phases. Then finally,
</p>

<p begin="00:01:27" end="00:01:30">it’s tested and released some time later.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:30" end="00:01:34">Now, if that takes a year, if that takes two
years, if that takes three years, the pace
</p>

<p begin="00:01:34" end="00:01:38">of technical change and innovation is such
that by the time you’ve got to the end,
</p>

<p begin="00:01:38" end="00:01:40">the landscape has changed around you.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:40" end="00:01:46">Also, that whole process is based around you
assuming that, at the start of this, you can
</p>

<p begin="00:01:46" end="00:01:49">predict everything that’s going to happen,
that you’re going to get everything right
</p>

<p begin="00:01:49" end="00:01:56">just by sitting and thinking about it. It’s
not actually true and if you look at systems
</p>

<p begin="00:01:56" end="00:02:01">that have millions or billions of users online,
such as Facebook, Google, Twitter, Amazon,
</p>

<p begin="00:02:01" end="00:02:06">they all use the Agile approach. The Agile
is far different. Essentially, I think Agile
</p>

<p begin="00:02:06" end="00:02:11">can be summed up as two statements, or two
questions; which is, “What do you want by
</p>

<p begin="00:02:11" end="00:02:15">Friday?” And how do I do it better than
last week?”
</p>

<p begin="00:02:15" end="00:02:19">We go through sort of an Agile iterative process.
So it’s not like we get a document, it’s
</p>

<p begin="00:02:19" end="00:02:25">not like somebody has to procure a whole set
of services that takes months to draw up exactly
</p>

<p begin="00:02:25" end="00:02:31">the requirements and throw it over the wall
to another company. It’s like we can have
</p>

<p begin="00:02:31" end="00:02:35">constant meetings, we can say we can do a
bit and then say, “Is this good enough?”
</p>

<p begin="00:02:35" end="00:02:40">and then make changes and stuff like that.
So basically, it’s a much more fluid process.
</p>

<p begin="00:02:40" end="00:02:45">There’s much less waste, there’s much
less getting everything perfect before throwing
</p>

<p begin="00:02:45" end="00:02:47">it over the wall.
</p>

<p begin="00:02:47" end="00:02:51">It’s very different for designers. We’re
not used to working that way, because normally
</p>

<p begin="00:02:51" end="00:02:54">the design happens first and then the programming
happens. But it’s actually really good in
</p>

<p begin="00:02:54" end="00:02:58">that we get a chance to iterate as well as
the programmers.
</p>

<p begin="00:02:58" end="00:03:05">So we deliver stuff very, very fast indeed.
I think traditionally within the civil service
</p>

<p begin="00:03:05" end="00:03:08">that very rapid pace of delivery isn’t something
that I’ve seen.
</p>

<p begin="00:03:08" end="00:03:15">I think that people aren’t really used to
using online government services because they’ve
</p>

<p begin="00:03:15" end="00:03:20">generally either not been there, or when they’ve
tried to do it, it’s not been as easy as
</p>

<p begin="00:03:20" end="00:03:21">they’d expect.
</p>

<p begin="00:03:21" end="00:03:26">Facebook is a very sticky experience; people
get addicted to it, people love using it,
</p>

<p begin="00:03:26" end="00:03:31">people enjoy interacting with it, they enjoy
interacting with Twitter. They feel and affection
</p>

<p begin="00:03:31" end="00:03:37">for these services. Whereas government services,
I think people feel painful, they feel clunky,
</p>

<p begin="00:03:37" end="00:03:43">they feel slow, they feel difficult to use.
They feel ancient, they feel historic. In
</p>

<p begin="00:03:43" end="00:03:48">this age of the internet, things move so quickly
that the design approaches and the look and
</p>

<p begin="00:03:48" end="00:03:53">feel, the user experience of these sites is
inadequate, really, compared to what people
</p>

<p begin="00:03:53" end="00:03:55">are actually used to in their day-to-day life.
</p>

<p begin="00:03:55" end="00:04:02">I think [Julius 0:03:57] has to make all our
services as good as a private service or the
</p>

<p begin="00:04:05" end="00:04:10">current online banks. They’re not necessarily
going to be easy, but we can get as close
</p>

<p begin="00:04:10" end="00:04:17">as possible. And if we can explain things
in plain English, we can hopefully make it
</p>

<p begin="00:04:18" end="00:04:23">as a quick transaction on something that you
might actually want to do again.
</p>

<p begin="00:04:23" end="00:04:29">Nobody likes change, but it happens. It’s
good to embrace it.
</p>

<p begin="00:04:29" end="00:04:36">Yes, I’m having fun. I think, like a lot
of people, if you’d have asked me a year
</p>

<p begin="00:04:38" end="00:04:43">ago would I be working for the government,
I’d have said no. I’d have never have
</p>

<p begin="00:04:43" end="00:04:50">considered it. But I think GDS is pushing
forward in new ways of working and also gives
</p>

<p begin="00:04:52" end="00:04:56">people an opportunity to make things that
actually matter.
</p>

<p begin="00:04:56" end="00:05:00">This is brilliant. This is the best job I’ve
ever had. It’s just so exciting. We’re
</p>

<p begin="00:05:00" end="00:05:07">doing something so big and it’s been really
successful. I’m working with some amazing
</p>

<p begin="00:05:07" end="00:05:14">people, really inspirational people. We’re
doing something that I feel is worthwhile,
</p>

<p begin="00:05:15" end="00:05:17">which is absolutely brilliant. It’s absolutely
brilliant.
</p>



 </div> </body> </tt>