<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"> <body> <div xml:id="captions">

<p begin="00:00:00" end="00:00:05">I’m Roger Oldham and I’m deputy director
for digital services and the Ministry of Justice.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:05" end="00:00:09">We’re creating a new digital services division
here at the Ministry of Justice, and that’s
</p>

<p begin="00:00:09" end="00:00:14">to act as a centre of expertise in helping
the department transform itself digitally.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:14" end="00:00:19">So it will be a unit which is filled with
specialist so that we have a range of specialist
</p>

<p begin="00:00:19" end="00:00:24">digital expertise. But it will also be about
helping the business build capability right
</p>

<p begin="00:00:24" end="00:00:31">across in a variety of different roles.
So, for senior management and policy and operational
</p>

<p begin="00:00:31" end="00:00:35">colleagues, that means that it’s about giving
them the understanding of what digital can
</p>

<p begin="00:00:35" end="00:00:40">do for their business area, helping them so
that they can have a degree of digital thinking
</p>

<p begin="00:00:40" end="00:00:45">that becomes part of their day-to-day.
In assessing the digital capability that we
</p>

<p begin="00:00:45" end="00:00:51">needed, the specialist skills that we needed
to bring into the ministry, we looked at how
</p>

<p begin="00:00:51" end="00:00:55">the best organisations deliver their digital
services. We worked with the government digital
</p>

<p begin="00:00:55" end="00:01:00">service to understand how they had developed
a specialist capability right at the centre
</p>

<p begin="00:01:00" end="00:01:05">of government, and we addressed the skills
gaps that we identified as a result.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:05" end="00:01:09">The kind of skills that you need to deliver
digital services effectively are quite different
</p>

<p begin="00:01:09" end="00:01:15">to the skills that you might typically find
in the civil service. And therefore a skillset
</p>

<p begin="00:01:15" end="00:01:19">that we needed to develop. So we had some
of the right expertise in some parts of the
</p>

<p begin="00:01:19" end="00:01:24">department, but certainly not enough of the
expertise that we needed across the board.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:24" end="00:01:28">In actual fact, when you look at the civil
service more broadly, typically people have
</p>

<p begin="00:01:28" end="00:01:33">moved around and had a general level of ability
in a wide range of different roles. Actually
</p>

<p begin="00:01:33" end="00:01:38">delivering digital services doesn’t play
to that particular model. So we’ve needed
</p>

<p begin="00:01:38" end="00:01:45">to bring in people who have got hands-on experience
of delivering great digital services and to
</p>

<p begin="00:01:45" end="00:01:50">actually use them to develop the capability
that we need. The ministry is the first department
</p>

<p begin="00:01:50" end="00:01:54">to be implementing a digital services division
in this way.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:54" end="00:01:58">An example of a service that we’re transforming
would be Legal Aid eligibility. Only those
</p>

<p begin="00:01:58" end="00:02:03">who are actually eligible come through to
the phone line and have the more detailed
</p>

<p begin="00:02:03" end="00:02:07">conversation with a specialist advisor. The
value of that particular service is to ensure
</p>

<p begin="00:02:07" end="00:02:13">that we don’t have significant numbers of
calls coming through to our call centres for
</p>

<p begin="00:02:13" end="00:02:18">people who are not eligible and who the specialists
are not able to help. So we can maintain,
</p>

<p begin="00:02:18" end="00:02:25">if you like, a level of service by ensuring
that people are diverted to alternative forms
</p>

<p begin="00:02:25" end="00:02:31">of help where appropriate, and reducing the
burden on the call centres that we’re operating.
</p>

<p begin="00:02:31" end="00:02:34">We’re certainly approaching the unit as
a pathfinder and working very closely with
</p>

<p begin="00:02:34" end="00:02:39">a government digital service to ensure that
we establish it in a way that not only links
</p>

<p begin="00:02:39" end="00:02:44">in well to the unit that they’ve set up
at the centre, but also could form a model
</p>

<p begin="00:02:44" end="00:02:50">for other departments to follow. It may be
possible in time for units to be shared across
</p>

<p begin="00:02:50" end="00:02:53">a number of departments.
For people who are looking to set up this
</p>

<p begin="00:02:53" end="00:02:58">kind of unit in other departments, I would
say that you need to have a very clear vision
</p>

<p begin="00:02:58" end="00:03:02">of what you’re trying to achieve. You need
to be, I think, focused on the fact that you’re
</p>

<p begin="00:03:02" end="00:03:06">not going to be able to do everything for
everybody so you need to very clear about
</p>

<p begin="00:03:06" end="00:03:11">what your priorities are. So the way in which
I’m approaching it is to look at the service
</p>

<p begin="00:03:11" end="00:03:18">we’re providing as if it’s a service to
the business that enables them to transform
</p>

<p begin="00:03:19" end="00:03:23">the business that they’re operating.
I would say to those who have the opportunity
</p>

<p begin="00:03:23" end="00:03:27">to come and work in government and to be part
of that, you won’t experience anything like
</p>

<p begin="00:03:27" end="00:03:32">it. There can be a lot of difficult issues,
which you have to cut through. It requires
</p>

<p begin="00:03:32" end="00:03:37">a lot of very clear communication, and a lot
of engagement, but it also requires you to
</p>

<p begin="00:03:37" end="00:03:42">be single-minded and not to be afraid of having
tough conversations and dealing with difficult
</p>

<p begin="00:03:42" end="00:03:49">issues and with conflict. This is an incredibly
motivating kind of role and the opportunity
</p>

<p begin="00:03:50" end="00:03:57">to really make a difference, to be contributing
towards something which is greater than yourself.
</p>

<p begin="00:03:58" end="00:03:58">How could I not be having fun?
</p>



 </div> </body> </tt>