<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"> <body> <div xml:id="captions">

<p begin="0:00:00.750" end="0:00:06.029">My name’s Alice Newton and I’m on the
graduate fast stream. I didn’t know any
</p>

<p begin="0:00:06.029" end="0:00:09.510">Agile before I came to the government
digital service, so I’ve had a chance to
</p>

<p begin="0:00:09.510" end="0:00:15.219">learn about Agile and how it works. For me
in particular it’s meant going out into
</p>

<p begin="0:00:15.219" end="0:00:21.010">departments where they have an idea of a product
they want, rewinding them a couple of steps
</p>

<p begin="0:00:21.010" end="0:00:27.470">and asking them to think about the user needs
that they’re actually trying to serve. Then
</p>

<p begin="0:00:27.470" end="0:00:32.279">working with them to see, building on the
user needs, what would be the right product
</p>

<p begin="0:00:32.279" end="0:00:35.140">to deliver.
It’s been a good experience. A lot of people
</p>

<p begin="0:00:35.140" end="0:00:39.280">around the departments have been quite hesitant
about trying Agile as it’s something very
</p>

<p begin="0:00:39.280" end="0:00:43.969">new to them. But I’ve universally found
on my projects that afterwards, they think
</p>

<p begin="0:00:43.969" end="0:00:46.700">it’s something they’d love to do again
and they’ve been really pleased with the
</p>

<p begin="0:00:46.700" end="0:00:51.850">outcome.
Number 10 dashboard has been my biggest product
</p>

<p begin="0:00:51.850" end="0:00:58.420">so far. It’s meant to be a dashboard to
give the Prime Minister and other senior officials
</p>

<p begin="0:00:58.420" end="0:01:04.960">the most up-to-date view on government priorities.
Whether that’s housing to national business
</p>

<p begin="0:01:04.960" end="0:01:11.180">or local growth, they should be able to open
the dashboard and the Prime Minister accesses
</p>

<p begin="0:01:11.180" end="0:01:16.290">it on his iPad. Once they’ve opened that
dashboard, they’ll have access to the latest
</p>

<p begin="0:01:16.290" end="0:01:22.670">government data and external data, as well
as commentary and analysis by top analysts
</p>

<p begin="0:01:22.670" end="0:01:25.540">in the government.
When the Prime Minister opens up the dashboard,
</p>

<p begin="0:01:25.540" end="0:01:31.350">the first thing he’ll see is a page giving
him the daily political context. This has
</p>

<p begin="0:01:31.350" end="0:01:35.159">been built with the input of the Prime Minister.
I was able to meet the Prime Minister after
</p>

<p begin="0:01:35.159" end="0:01:40.900">we’d finished the alpha version of the app
and show it to him and get some direct feedback,
</p>

<p begin="0:01:40.900" end="0:01:45.090">which was of course incredibly valuable, to
be able to speak to your users. My favourite
</p>

<p begin="0:01:45.090" end="0:01:49.170">thing that he said was that he liked it so
much, he was looking forward to showing it
</p>

<p begin="0:01:49.170" end="0:01:54.880">to Obama at the G8.
I would love to tell senior civil servants
</p>

<p begin="0:01:54.880" end="0:01:59.149">about all the opportunities that exist in
digital, and how fast streamers are some of
</p>

<p begin="0:01:59.149" end="0:02:03.770">the best people to take advantage of them,
since me and the people younger than me are
</p>

<p begin="0:02:03.770" end="0:02:08.660">probably the first generation of digital natives
coming through. I’m having a lot of fun.
</p>

<p begin="0:02:08.660" end="0:02:15.660">It’s been a brilliant first job to come
into, really. It’s great to be in an organisation
</p>

<p begin="0:02:16.150" end="0:02:20.720">where Post-Its are thrown up on the walls,
everyone feels very relaxed, you’re allowed
</p>

<p begin="0:02:20.720" end="0:02:26.260">to have ideas, you’re encouraged to have
ideas. You’re working on some really important
</p>

<p begin="0:02:26.260" end="0:02:31.379">projects for this country and, yes, just enjoying
it while you do it.
</p>



 </div> </body> </tt>