<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"> <body> <div xml:id="captions">

<p begin="00:00:00" end="00:00:06">Hi, I’m Francis Maude. I’m minister for
the cabinet office. I have the pleasure of
</p>

<p begin="00:00:06" end="00:00:10">having responsibility for the government’s
policy of digital by default.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:10" end="00:00:15">These days, people’s expectations are very
high of how they do things in their ordinary
</p>

<p begin="00:00:15" end="00:00:20">life. People don’t think of doing things
digitally as being about technology; it’s
</p>

<p begin="00:00:20" end="00:00:25">just part of their life. And so much that
they do is done online. If you’re booking
</p>

<p begin="00:00:25" end="00:00:30">an airline ticket, anything like that, you
do it online. But in government, we’re way,
</p>

<p begin="00:00:30" end="00:00:36">way behind, which gives us a fantastic opportunity
to do things really better. That’s what
</p>

<p begin="00:00:36" end="00:00:39">we’re doing. There’s less money around
so we need to do it more cheaply as well as
</p>

<p begin="00:00:39" end="00:00:45">giving citizens a better experience.
We made a lot of progress moving onto gov.uk,
</p>

<p begin="00:00:45" end="00:00:49">which is going to be so much easier for people
to get information about what’s going on
</p>

<p begin="00:00:49" end="00:00:55">in government. Now we need to move the next
step to get transactions done online.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:55" end="00:00:59">We’ve got lots of good examples of that,
but people don’t use them enough, and we
</p>

<p begin="00:00:59" end="00:01:05">need to make these applications absolutely
compelling so that it’s so intuitive, it’s
</p>

<p begin="00:01:05" end="00:01:09">so easy, it’s such a natural thing to do
that people don’t even think twice about
</p>

<p begin="00:01:09" end="00:01:15">whether they renew their car tax online or
any other of the myriad different things that
</p>

<p begin="00:01:15" end="00:01:21">we have to do with government. So I’m really
excited with this. There’s a huge amount
</p>

<p begin="00:01:21" end="00:01:26">to do, but so much upside from it, there’s
so much ability for us to do things better
</p>

<p begin="00:01:26" end="00:01:30">and give our citizens a better experience.
That’s what we’re here for. Thanks.
</p>



 </div> </body> </tt>