<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"> <body> <div xml:id="captions">

<p begin="00:00:00" end="00:00:06">My name is Marketta, and I’m CEO of Go ON
UK. Go ON UK is a charity and our aim is to
</p>

<p begin="00:00:06" end="00:00:10">make the UK the most digitally capable nation
in the world.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:10" end="00:00:15">Core to our belief is a belief in digital
by default. I think the important thing to
</p>

<p begin="00:00:15" end="00:00:22">underscore there is digital by default; not
digital only. So that means when we’re thinking
</p>

<p begin="00:00:23" end="00:00:27">about how we’re conceiving of services for
the future, we need to think about digital
</p>

<p begin="00:00:27" end="00:00:31">at the heart because of what that can deliver
in terms of customer experience and efficiency,
</p>

<p begin="00:00:31" end="00:00:36">and a whole host of other things.
That’s not to say there shouldn’t be support
</p>

<p begin="00:00:36" end="00:00:42">for those can’t access the service. We think
that that’s critical again as part of not
</p>

<p begin="00:00:42" end="00:00:47">leaving anyone behind that that is catered
for, and we know that assisted digital is
</p>

<p begin="00:00:47" end="00:00:52">being addressed. We think that’s a critical
part of the support that needs to be in place.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:52" end="00:00:57">I suppose we would aim to get to 100% because
we think that the internet is an amazing place
</p>

<p begin="00:00:57" end="00:01:02">to be and we’d love for everyone to join.
I think the reality is that some people might
</p>

<p begin="00:01:02" end="00:01:07">opt out of that choice, but we’d like for
that to be an active opt out, and informed
</p>

<p begin="00:01:07" end="00:01:13">opt out. So fundamentally, we believe that
no one deserves to be left behind because
</p>

<p begin="00:01:13" end="00:01:17">of cost barriers, because the infrastructure
isn’t there, because they haven’t the
</p>

<p begin="00:01:17" end="00:01:21">skills. I think that’s the most important
thing; it should be an active choice and not
</p>

<p begin="00:01:21" end="00:01:26">one that you’re not able to avail yourself
of because of the barriers.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:26" end="00:01:31">The flavour of assisted digital will be as
varied as the customer need, and I think that
</p>

<p begin="00:01:31" end="00:01:34">we’re all collectively still on a journey
of trying to understand that because of the
</p>

<p begin="00:01:34" end="00:01:41">complexity and variety of government transaction.
I think that the hardware interface is serving
</p>

<p begin="00:01:41" end="00:01:47">as a barrier to a lot of people, so the intimidation
of a keyboard or of a mouse, and as we transcend
</p>

<p begin="00:01:47" end="00:01:54">into mobile touch-based interaction, that’s
bringing down a lot of barriers for people.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:54" end="00:01:58">So I think we’re going to see a significant
shift as there is changes in hardware that
</p>

<p begin="00:01:58" end="00:02:03">allow us to access that place that will open
people’s mind to the possibility.
</p>



 </div> </body> </tt>