<tt xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/10/ttaf1"> <body> <div xml:id="captions">

<p begin="00:00:00" end="00:00:04">The redesign of our services or our taxes
is probably a big challenge to us that needs
</p>

<p begin="00:00:04" end="00:00:08">to be understood by everybody who’s listening
to this. You know, we have digitalised before
</p>

<p begin="00:00:08" end="00:00:13">just existing practices and therefore it brings
challenge. If you take self-assessment for
</p>

<p begin="00:00:13" end="00:00:18">example, a great online service, but you can’t
pay online. You just took the old practices
</p>

<p begin="00:00:18" end="00:00:19">and actually digitalised them.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:19" end="00:00:24">What we need to do now and what we are doing
is business process re-engineering, taking
</p>

<p begin="00:00:24" end="00:00:30">every single process we have, every core tax,
and re-designing it completely in an end-to-end
</p>

<p begin="00:00:30" end="00:00:34">way, and then digitalising it. That sounds
so obvious and rudimentary now if you think
</p>

<p begin="00:00:34" end="00:00:38">about, but in fact for us that’s a major
breakthrough. Taking a tax, no matter where
</p>

<p begin="00:00:38" end="00:00:43">it sits in the organisation, no matter what
the hierarchy or the departmental siloes are
</p>

<p begin="00:00:43" end="00:00:46">that manage it, redesigning it and then digitalising
it.
</p>

<p begin="00:00:46" end="00:00:50">HMRC over the years has suffered from something
other parts of government have suffered with
</p>

<p begin="00:00:50" end="00:00:55">before. That is, we try to invent everything
for ourselves. We haven’t looked at the
</p>

<p begin="00:00:55" end="00:00:59">market to do stuff; we’ve done it for ourselves.
One of the biggest challenges we’ve found
</p>

<p begin="00:00:59" end="00:01:05">when we did self-assessment online is that
people needed some payroll mechanism to record
</p>

<p begin="00:01:05" end="00:01:10">and provide data to us and employers needed
the same. Therefore, we began to give away
</p>

<p begin="00:01:10" end="00:01:16">free software. That is very simple, very generic
software, it enabled them to do things with
</p>

<p begin="00:01:16" end="00:01:18">us in the PAYE space.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:18" end="00:01:21">The biggest challenge of course, actually
the market said, “We could do better. We
</p>

<p begin="00:01:21" end="00:01:25">could actually add it into other features,
we could sell it as part of a service.”
</p>

<p begin="00:01:25" end="00:01:29">But of course HMRC said, “No, no. It’s
us. We’re HMRC. It’s kind of unique stuff.”
</p>

<p begin="00:01:29" end="00:01:34">But of course, we began increasingly to realise
we couldn’t keep up with the market. We
</p>

<p begin="00:01:34" end="00:01:38">couldn’t featurise it, we couldn’t make
it very rich. The market began demand of us
</p>

<p begin="00:01:38" end="00:01:45">access to those core mechanisms or APIs, the
core infrastructure that goes behind the coding
</p>

<p begin="00:01:45" end="00:01:49">of those payroll solutions. So we began to
give it away.
</p>

<p begin="00:01:49" end="00:01:54">We found the payroll industry took it way
beyond anything we could ever have done. It’s
</p>

<p begin="00:01:54" end="00:01:58">built a strong relationship between us and
the payroll market, so much so, things like
</p>

<p begin="00:01:58" end="00:02:04">real-time, the actual modernisation of PAYE,
is being done through these payroll providers.
</p>

<p begin="00:02:04" end="00:02:09">And because we have had such a strong relationship,
it’s been a very powerful joint approach
</p>

<p begin="00:02:09" end="00:02:11">to the new way to do PAYE.
</p>

<p begin="00:02:11" end="00:02:15">We are eight or nine years into this journey,
and of course I’m describing the end result
</p>

<p begin="00:02:15" end="00:02:18">to you, which sounds great. But looking back,
it didn’t need to be this long and didn’t
</p>

<p begin="00:02:18" end="00:02:23">need to be this painful. I would encourage
anybody thinking about this or designing like
</p>

<p begin="00:02:23" end="00:02:27">this, I think you should start with a default;
you’ll give it away, and then decide you’re
</p>

<p begin="00:02:27" end="00:02:28">not going to, rather than the other way around.
</p>

<p begin="00:02:28" end="00:02:33">Secondly, it’s the culture of the organisation.
Giving anything away in government is always
</p>

<p begin="00:02:33" end="00:02:37">seen as a problem or needs to be checked,
or committees and lawyers and all sorts need
</p>

<p begin="00:02:37" end="00:02:41">to have their penny’s worth in that. But
if you design it with that in mind, I think
</p>

<p begin="00:02:41" end="00:02:46">it’s very powerful. Give it away, of course
you’ll find the market will enrich it dramatically
</p>

<p begin="00:02:46" end="00:02:50">and give back to you a much richer experience
and perhaps, in our case, a better set of
</p>

<p begin="00:02:50" end="00:02:52">data that’s of a higher quality.
</p>



 </div> </body> </tt>